Damian Mandola Jr.

LinkedIn: http://www.linkedin.com/in/damianjr (713) 824-6195 dmandola11@gmail.com

After spending over ten years in restaurant and bakery management I have focused on switching fields to start a career in web development. I have always been intrigued and fascinated with technology and especially enjoy the creativity involved in front end development. With my background in customer service and management, I look forward to creating professional, responsive and user-friendly websites as part of my new career.

EDUCATION

UNIVERSITY OF TEXAS

Austin, TX

Coding Boot Camp- Full Stack Web Development, Jul 2016 - Feb 2017

BOSTON UNIVERSITY

Boston, MA

BA, International Relations, September 2002 - May 2006

- Degree in International Relations with a focus on International Systems and World Order
- Student Leader for Project Hope, Community Service Center
- BU Red Cross Volunteer

JOHN CABOT UNIVERSITY

Rome, Italy

Study Abroad Program, September 2004 - May 2005

SKILLS

- Programming languages: HTML, CSS, Javascript, Jquery, Node. is, Express, SQL, MongoDB, React. is
- Limited working proficiency in Spanish and moderate proficiency in Italian (dual Italian citizenship)
- Comprehensive experience with computer software including Aloha POS, Hotschedules and Microsoft Office

WORK EXPERIENCE

InstacartFull Service Shopper

Austin

Aug 2016 – Present

Mandola's Italian Market

Austin, TX

Manager

Jan 2013 - Jul 2016

- Achieve company objectives in sales, service, quality, appearance of facility and sanitation and cleanliness through training of employees and creating a positive, productive working environment.
- Prepare all required paperwork, including forms, reports and schedules in an organized and timely manner.
- Ensure that all guests feel welcome and are given attentive, friendly and courteous service at all times.
- Establish standards for personnel performance and customer service.

Bakery Director

Mar 2012 - Jan 2013

- Directly responsible for implementing and following company bakery standards and overseeing the bakery operations of all stores as well as inter-store deliveries.
- Meet with customers to discuss menus for special occasions, such as weddings, parties, or banquets.
- Analyze recipes to assign prices to menu items, based on food, labor, and overhead costs.

Mandola's Italian Market Bee Cave, TX

General Manager Mar 2009 – Feb 2012

• Oversee and coordinate the planning, organizing, training, and leadership necessary to achieve stated objectives in sales, costs, profitability, employee retention, guest service and satisfaction, food quality, cleanliness, and sanitation.

- Manage staff, preparing work schedules through Hotschedules and assigning specific duties.
- Achieve company objectives in sales, service, quality, appearance of facility, sanitation, and cleanliness through training of employees and by creating a positive and productive working environment.

Mandola's Italian Market Austin, TX

Floor Manager

Jun 2006 - Mar 2009

- Understand completely all policies, procedures, standards, specifications, guidelines and training programs.
- Ensure that all guests feel welcome and are given attentive, friendly and courteous service at all times.
- Control cash and other receipts by adhering to cash handling and reconciliation procedures in accordance with restaurant policies and procedures.